## **SERENGETI JADE ABREU**

• (508) 237-1093 • jad245@gmail.com • serengetijade.github.io • linkedin.com/in/serengetijade •

# **Experience Summary**

Software developer with experience as a team member on C#, Python, and cyber security projects to develop new or existing applications, as well as to perform penetration testing and attack investigations. Strong understanding of core CIS concepts and object oriented programming. Experienced in managing small businesses; number one in sales for four consecutive years; excellent communication and customer service skills.

# <u>Skills</u>

Programing C#, Python, JavaScript, Java, SQL, Typescript, HTMI, CSS

**Frameworks & Etc** MVC design pattern, .NET, Django, Angular, jQuery, Bootstrap, Tkinter **Cyber Security** Network and security principles, Avast, Wireshark and PCAP analysis,

Malwarebytes, Burp Suite, Snort3, Avast, CCleaner

IDEs VS Code, Visual Studio, PyCharm, IDLE, IntelliJ IDEA, Android Studio

**Version Control** Git, GitHub, Azure

Other Google Workspace, Excell, Power Point, Microsoft Word, SketchUp, POS

**Business Domains** Finance, marketing, international travel

**Soft skills** Customer service, sales, communication, management

**Languages** Conversational in Spanish

## Education

# The Tech Academy, Portland, OR

May 2023

Software Engineering Certificate, Cyber Security Certificate

Academic Honors: Honors Certificate

# Bentley University, Waltham, MA

May 2008

Bachelor in Finance; Concentrations: Marketing, International Studies (GPA 3.5)

Academic Honors: Honors Program, Presidential Scholarship, Dean's List

Leadership Positions: Resident Assistant 2006-2008

Internship: Barclays Bank- KYC Division, London, England 2007

# **Professional Experience**

# **Software Engineering Intern, Cyber Security Intern** *Prosper IT*, Portland, OR

June 2022 - May 2023

- Fundamentals of Computer Science, software development, object-oriented programming, MVC, CRUD, databases and data structures, Azure DevOps, Git, Visual Studio, VS Code
- C# and Entity Framework: a web app for a Portland theater company.
  - Created a database for storing comments
  - Created and styled a comment page to allow users to create comments. Implemented partial views for code reuse
  - Added administrator role to delete comments, included a pop up confirmation of deletion
  - Built a page to upload blog images, edit the titles, and delete unwanted images
  - Languages and Libraries: C#, JavaScript, jQuery, AJAX, Bootstrap, HTML, CSS
- Python and Diango Framework: created a web application to track users' games
  - Created a database with full CRUD functionality. Users can create and update records of the games they own, add and remove items from a wish list
  - API and web scraping: users can read reviews generated as page elements by web scraping with beautifulsoup, search API results based on user input, and add any of those to their wish list
  - Languages and Libraries: Python, Django, Django Template Language, JavaScript,

HTML. CSS. XML

- Cyber Security Bootcamp: applied network security practices such as Snort3, firewalls, and virus scanners.
  - Performed ethical hacking and vulnerability assessment on web application, such as SQL injection, blunt force attacks, XSS, authority escalation, request interception, etc.
  - Analyzed infected Windows OS to remove ransomware
  - Reviewed PCAP files to determine attack vectors, identify malware, and propose new security measures.
  - Implemented Malwarebytes removal software to remove adware from an infected device
- AngularJS Framework: a product management web app
  - Embedded features into html such as if conditions, for loops, and local variables
  - Bound values to variables and executed logic using those values. Created strongly typed objects using Typescript from a JSON file
  - Read data to display in a table format. Used event binding for dynamic display elements.
  - Updated display based on filter inputs
  - Languages and Libraries: Angular, Typescript, JavaScript, JSON, ¡Query, HTML, CSS.

**Cerulean Winery** 

Dec 2021 – Present Tasting Room Manager, Hood River, OR

- Built relationships with new and existing guests, determined preferences, and matched clients to appropriate products to generate sales
- Maintained sales software (WineDirect) by creating and editing products, updating client records, and processing sales and commission reports
- Managed tasting room operations- customer service communications, inventory, upkeep, etc
- Processed quarterly wine club- prepared and shipped orders, created marketing brochures. updated club accounts, responded to member requests and emails, etc

**Evoke Winery** May 2017 - August 2021

Tasting Room Associate, Hood River, OR

- Highest number of club sales in 2018, 2019, 2020, and 2021\* (\*year to date)
- Aided in the transition of new branding strategy and provided friendly customer service
- Promoted and sold tickets to special events, trips, and weekend vacation packages

#### **Interim Experiences**

International Travel

Jan 2012- June 2019

- Traveled independently to 7 continents and over 75 countries
- Researched, planned, and organized logistics for trips up to 6 months in duration
- Self funded, budgeted, and created itineraries for each adventure
- Personally experienced various cultures, customs, histories, perspectives and lifestyles
- Please see the Appendix for a list of countries visited and seasonal jobs held during this time

#### Merrill Lynch Global Wealth Investment Management

Financial Advisor, Washington, DC

Dec 2010 - Jan 2012

- Provided personalized and detailed financial planning advice based on client goals
- Offered technical support to clients using online investment platform
- Created portfolio and investment reports using proprietary software
- Marketed and independently managed investment portfolios for high net worth clients, accounting for client needs, time horizon, and risk tolerance
- Received coaching in investment and wealth management through PMD Program
- Performance at 812% above standard

#### **Edward Jones Investments**

Financial Advisor, Easton, MD

Aug 2008 - Mar 2009, Oct 2009 - Dec 2010

• Recognized for performance above 100% of standard for 4 consecutive quarters

Offices in Transition, Saint Louis, MO

May – October, 2009

- Retained and expanded client relationships by reviewing and updating portfolio allocation
- Supervised branch operations including inventory and local marketing
- Recipient of Recognition Award for Outstanding Performance

## References

Tracy Thomsen: Training Director, Timberline Lodge (206)-240-1161 Ashley Pacelli: Guest Service Manager, GeoEx (760) 310-2068

Lindsey Ewald: Co Owner & 2017-2020 Tasting Room Manager, Evoke Winery (541) 490-7065

Chelsea Cote: Director of HR, Gorton's Seafood (860) 874-3608

Autumn Walker: former supervisor at Mt Hood Meadows (541) 380-1575

## **APPENDIX**

## **Countries of Travel**

Africa: Ethiopia, Egypt, Kenya, Rwanda, Seychelles, Tanzania, Uganda

Asia: Brunei, Cambodia, Hong Kong, India, Indonesia, Laos, Macau, Malaysia, Myanmar,

Nepal, Philippines, Qatar, Singapore, Sri Lanka, Taiwan, Thailand, Turkey, Vietnam

Antarctica: Antarctic Peninsula
Australasia: Australia, New Zealand

**Europe and Eastern Europe:** Albania, Austria, Bosnia and Herzegovina, Bulgaria, Croatia, Cyprus, England, Gibraltar, Greece, Hungary, Kosovo, Macedonia, Montenegro, Romania,

Scotland, Serbia, Slovenia, Spain, Switzerland, Whales

North America: Canada, Mexico

South America: Argentina, Bolivia, Chile, Ecuador, Paragua, Peru, Uruguay

Caribbean and Central America: Antigua and Barbuda, Aruba, Bahamas, Barbados, British Virgin Islands, Cayman Islands, Costa Rica, Curacao, Dominican Republic, El Salvador, Guatemala, Honduras, Jamaica, Nicaragua, Panama, Saint Lucia, Saint Kitts, St Martin, St Thomas, Trinidad and Tobago

## **Hobbies**

- International Travel
- Reading: the BBC Big Read List
- Outdoors: hiking (300 mile Maine section of the Appalachian Trail), camping; MYOG (MyOwnGear), gardening
- Snowsports: snowboarding and skiing

# **Interim Work Experience**

Between trips abroad, I worked various seasonal jobs to earn funds for my travels. The positions listed below are seasonal: a full commitment is for a single season.

#### Ski and Ride School. Timberline Ski Resort

Ski and Snowboard Instructor, Mt Hood, Oregon

Dec 2019 - March 2020

- Taught beginner and intermediate ski and snowboard lessons
- Introduced new skiers and snowboarders to the sport by performing introductory lessons
- Provided targeted exercises to fix problems or acquire new skills

- Assessed riders and offered personalized feedback and advice for refining techniques
- Supervised activities, with groups of up to 13 students, to ensure a safe and fun environment
- Fulfilled seasonal commitment in advance of 2020 shutdown, which closed the resort early Referral: Steve Muise (503) 272-3707

# Ski and Ride School, Copper Mountain Resort

Nov 2018 - April 2019

Ski and Snowboard Instructor, Frisco, CO

- Taught beginner and intermediate ski and snowboard lessons
- Obtained PSIA Ski Instructor Level 1 certificate

#### **CB Grille, Copper Mountain Resort**

Nov 2018 - April 2019

Waitstaff, Frisco, CO

- Provided excellent and attentive customer service in a fine dining establishment
- Presented detailed information about food and wine selections, ensured perfect table set up, and anticipated customer needs regarding water, bread, cutlery changes, etc

**Incline Bar & Grill** 

Nov 2018 - April 2019

Waitstaff, Frisco, CO

• Serviced high volume lunch crowds during height of ski season

#### Ski and Ride School, Keystone Resort

Ski and Snowboard Instructor, Keystone, CO

Nov 2018 - April 2019

- Taught beginner and intermediate ski and snowboard lessons at Mountain House school
- Obtained USASA Snowboard Instructor Level 1 certificate

# Alpenstube Restaurant, Base Lodge, Mt Hood Meadows Ski Resort

Wait Staff, Mt Hood, OR

Dec 2015 - April 2017

- Served as full time waitress during lunch and dinner; managed cash bank
- Received Outstanding Employee Award, December 2015
- Early or punctual for every shift, never late once

Referral: Mark Fellows or Barbara Gerhardt (503) 337-2222

#### Sitting Bull, Base Lodge, Okemo Mountain Resort

Wait Staff, Ludlow, VT

Nov 2014 – March 2015

• Earned seven Difference Awards for excellent customer service during lunch and apres service

Referral: Rick Doyle (802) 228-1600

#### Red Nun Bar & Grill

Wait Staff, Chatham, MA

June 2004 - Oct 2006, Sept 2012 - 2014

• Provided friendly, professional customer service as a waitress during lunch and dinner Referral: Mike or Fred (508) 348-0469

# **Chatham Squire Restaurant**

Wait Staff, Chatham, MA

June 2000 - Oct 2007

- Efficiently served as waitress during lunch, dinner, and cocktailing shifts
- Covered shifts as hostess, busser, runner, expeditor, and kitchen hand to help when the restaurant was busy or short handed

Referral: Karen Marjollet (508) 945-0945